Always be yourself...unless you can be Batman.
The Lego Batman Movie is a animation, action,
comedy film directed by Chris McKay.
A cooler-than-ever Bruce Wayne must deal with the usual suspects as they plan to rule Gotham City, while
discovering that he has accidentally adopted a teenage orphan who wishes to become his sidekick.
Batman / Bruce Wayne (voice), played by Will Arnett.
Robin / Dick Grayson (voice), played by Michael Cera.
Batgirl / Barbara Gordon (voice), played by Rosario Dawson.
Alfred Pennyworth (voice), played by Ralph Fiennes.
Joker (voice), played by Zach Galifianakis.
Harley Quinn (voice), played by Jenny Slate.
The Lego Batman Movie is a 2017 animated superhero comedy film, based on
characters created by DC Comics and the Lego Batman toy line.
It was directed by Chris McKay from a screenplay that
is based on a Seth Grahame-Smith story.
The film is a collaboration between production houses from the United States, Australia, and Denmark,
the first spin-off in The Lego Movie franchise and the second installment overall.
The film features Will Arnett reprising his role as Batman from The Lego Movie
alongside Zach Galifianakis, Michael Cera, Rosario Dawson and Ralph Fiennes.
The story follows Batman as he attempts to overcome his greatest fear
while saving Gotham City from the Joker's latest scheme.
Development of The Lego Batman Movie started in October 2014, after Warner Bros.
announced several Lego films, following the critical and
commercial success of The Lego Movie.
Chris McKay was hired to direct after being replaced by Rob Schrab as director of the
sequel to The Lego Movie, who then cited both The Naked Gun and the Airplane!
as his main inspirations while casting calls began in July to November 2015.
The film pays homage to previous Batman media and also features characters
from other notable franchises and film series with them.
Like The Lego Movie, the animation was provided by Animal Logic.
Lorne Balfe composed the musical score.
The Lego Batman Movie had its world premiere in Dublin, Ireland on
January 29, 2017, and was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures in U.S.
theaters on February 10.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics for its animation, voice acting, music, visual style and humor,
and was also commercially successful, having grossed $312 million worldwide against a budget of $80 million.
A sequel, Lego Superfriends, was announced in 2018, but was cancelled after
Universal Pictures acquired the film rights to the Lego brand in 2020.
The film explores themes of superhero, based on comic,
based on toy, spin off, super power.
The tone is lighthearted.